Zhen Wang

CSE, The Ohio State University 274 Dreese Lab, 2015 Neil Ave Columbus, OH 43210

RESEARCH **INTERESTS**

I am interested in empowering current AI systems with more explicit and humanunderstandable knowledge, aiming to make them more generalizable, interpretable, and efficient. My research lies in the nexus of natural language processing, deep learning, and data mining, where I study a "full stack" of the knowledge-centric AI from ground up: acquisition, representation, and reasoning. My long-term research goal is to transfuse the strengths of human knowledge systems (e.g., intuitive physics, commonsense reasoning) to the next evolution of AI systems.

- Knowledge Acquisition: Structured knowledge extraction from text and graphs, Knowledge Graph construction, Knowledge distillation from language models
- Knowledge Representation: Word representation learning, Graph embedding learning, Graph neural networks, Commonsense concept learning
- Knowledge Reasoning: Multi-hop reasoning over text and graphs (KG reasoning, complex QA), Neuro-symbolic reasoning, Commonsense reasoning
- Applications: Natural language interfaces (dialogue systems, question answering), Controllable text generation, Clinical NLP (e.g., knowledge discovery on clinical notes), Bioinformatics

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University (OSU)

PhD Candidate, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Advisor: Huan Sun (Since Autumn 2017)

Université Nice Sophia Antipolis (UNS)

Visiting Student, Polytech Nice Sophia Individual Study Advisor: Lionel Fillatre and Michel Barlaud

China University of Petroleum (UPC)

B.S. in Electronic Information Engineering Graduated as 1st-Ranked Student in the Major Overall Ranking

WORK **EXPERIENCE**

The Ohio State University

Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Advisor: Huan Sun

MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab Cambridge, MA, USA Research Intern, Hosted by Rameswar Panda and Yoon Kim Summer 2022 Topic: Multi-task prompt tuning for efficient adaptation of large language models

Microsoft Research Redmond

Redmond, WA, USA Research Intern, Hosted by Nebojsa Jojic Summer 2021 Topic: Coherence boosting and prompt calibration for large language models (e.g., GPT-3)

NEC Labs America

Princeton, NJ, USA Research Intern, Hosted by Bo Zong Summer 2020 Topic: Learning word embeddings by commonsense knowledge reasoning

The Ohio State University

Teaching Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

Columbus, OH, USA Autumn 2017

Email: wang.9215@osu.edu

Website: https://zhenwang9102.github.io

Phone: +1 (614) 805-9913

Columbus, OH, USA

2016-Present

Nice, France

Qingdao, China

Columbus, OH, USA

2011-2015

2018-Present

2015

PUBLICATIONS (* equal contribution)

Knowledge Transfer between Structured and Unstructured Sources for Complex Question Answering

Lingbo Mo*, Zhen Wang*, Jie Zhao, Huan Sun
NAACL 2022 Structured and Unstructured Knowledge Integration (SUKI) [Paper]

Learning Interpretable Word Representations by Commonsense Knowledge Reasoning

Zhen Wang, Bo Zong, Wei Cheng, Xuchao Zhang, Yanchi Liu, Wenchao Yu, Jingchao Ni, Haifeng Chen, Huan Sun In Submission.

• Coherence Boosting: When Your Pretrained Language Model is Not Paying Enough Attention

Nikolay Malkin, <u>Zhen Wang</u>, Nebojsa Jojic *Proceedings of ACL* **2022** [Paper]

• Bootstrapping a User-Centered Task-Oriented Dialogue System

Shijie Chen, Ziru Chen, Xiang Deng, Ashley Lewis, Lingbo Mo, Samuel Stevens, Zhen Wang, Xiang Yue, Tianshu Zhang, Yu Su, Huan Sun

1st Proceedings of Alexa Prize TaskBot (Alexa Prize 2021) [Paper]

• Modeling Context Pair Interaction for Pairwise Tasks on Graphs
Zhen Wang, Bo Zong, Huan Sun

Proceedings of WSDM 2021 (Acceptance Rate: 18.6%, Long) [Paper]

Rationalizing Medical Relation Prediction from Corpus-level Statistics
 Zhen Wang, Jennifer Lee, Simon Lin, Huan Sun
 Proceedings of ACL 2020 (Acceptance Rate: 22.7%, Long) [Paper]

SurfCon: Synonym Discovery on Privacy-Aware Clinical Data
 Zhen Wang, Xiang Yue, Soheil Moosavinasab, Yungui Huang, Simon Lin, Huan Sun Proceeding of SIGKDD 2019 (Research Track, Acceptance Rate 14.2%, Oral) [Paper]

• Graph Embedding on Biomedical Networks: Methods, Applications, and Evaluations

Xiang Yue, Zhen Wang, Jingong Huang, Srinivasan Parthasarathy, Soheil Moosavinasab, Yungui Huang, Simon M. Lin, Wen Zhang, Ping Zhang, Huan Sun *Bioinformatics*, *Volume 36*, *Issue 4*, *15 February 2020*, *Pages 1241–1251* (Impact factor: 5.610) [Paper]

A Comprehensive Study of StaQC for Deep Code Summarization
 Jayavardhan Reddy Peddamail, Ziyu Yao, Zhen Wang, Huan Sun
 Proceedings of SIGKDD 2018 (Deep Learning Day, SPOTLIGHT) [Paper]

Hessian Regularized Sparse Coding for Human Action Recognition
Weifeng Liu, Zhen Wang, Dapeng Tao, Jun Yu
Proceedings of MMM 2015, Sydney, Australia [Paper]

HONORS AND AWARDS

Third-Place Honor, Inaugural Alexa Prize TaskBot Challenge	2022
Graduate Research Award, CSE, OSU	2022
 Graduate Student Research Poster Award (Top 5), CSE, OSU 	2021
SIGIR Student Travel Grant	2021
Rising Star in Data Science, CDAC, University of Chicago	2020
SIGKDD Student Travel Award	2019
• Excellent Bachelor Degree Thesis Award in Shandong Province, China	2016
Excellent Graduate Thesis Award of UPC, China	2015
China Scholarship Council (CSC) Scholarship	2015

- A fully supported visiting program in Polytech Nice Sophia, Nice, France

National Scholarship, China	2014
 Soong Ching Ling Foundation (SCLF) Scholarship, China 	2013
National Scholarship for Encouragement, China	2012

SERVICE

- Program Committee:
 - ACL ARR (Oct'21, Nov'21, Jan'22, April'22)
 - AAAI 2023
 - EMNLP 2021, 2022
 - ACL 2021
 - NAACL 2021
 - NLPCC (2020, 2021, 2022)
- External Reviewer: KDD (2019, 2020), ACL 2018, ICDM 2018

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• CSE 5525: Foundations of Speech and Language Processing

- ⊢ *OSU, Department of Computer Science & Engineering* Instructor, Autumn 2022 (>50 students)
- Tutorial: Natural Language Processing in Deep Learning Summer School
 - ⊢ *OSU, Foundations of Data Science and AI Community of Practice* Panelist, June 1 June 3, 2022 (>180 attendees)
- CSE 2111: Modeling and Problem Solving with Spreadsheets and Databases
 - ► *OSU*, *Department of Computer Science & Engineering* Teaching Assistant, Autumn 2017
- Panel Discussion: 2001: A Space Odyssey Science Fiction vs Science Fact
 - ⊢ *OSU*, *Department of Astronomy* Panelist, Feb. 2021

TALKS

- "Modeling Context Pair Interaction for Pairwise Tasks on Graphs", WSDM 2021, March, Online
- "SurfCon: Synonym Discovery on Privacy-Aware Clinical Data", KDD 2019, August 6, Anchorage, Alaska, USA
- "Rationalizing Relation Prediction from Corpus-level Staistics", ACL 2020, July, Online

REFERENCES

Available upon request